Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Herbert Eames Papers, 1974-1985 and undated RL.00688
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Herbert Eames papers
1974-1985 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00688
2 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Herbert Eames was an executive at JWT and served as the company's Chief Financial Officer and Executive Vice President of Finance and Administration between 1980-1984. The Herbert Eames Papers cover the period of 1974-1985, with the bulk of the material spanning 1980-1984, during which time Eames served as Chief Financial Officer at JWT. The papers relate to the operations and finances of JWT offices and subsidiaries around the world. The collection includes memos, correspondence, press releases, clippings, and materials relating to management meetings, and reports on financial, administrative, operational, valuation and real estate matters. Companies represented include JWT subsidiaries such as Hill and Knowlton, Brouillard Communications, Lansdowne, Thompson Recruitment Advertising and JWT Canada, and clients such as Kraft, along with JWT offices in Chicago and Frankfurt. Collection also touches on relations with Gray and Company. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
1500 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Herbert Eames Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1961 Employed by Nestlé
1963 Employed by McCalls Corporation
1967 Employed by Bristol-Myers Company
1977 Vice President and Corporate Controller, Woolworth Company
1980 July 1 Hired as Executive Vice President--Finance and Chief Financial Officer
1982 Jan. 1 Executive Vice President--Finance and Administration and Chief Financial officer at JWT
1984 July Resigned from JWT
Collection Overview
The Herbert Eames Papers covers the period of 1974-1985, with the bulk of the material spanning 1980-1984, during which Eames served as Chief Financial Officer at JWT. The papers relate to the operations and finances of JWT offices and subsidiaries around the world. The collection includes memos, correspondence, press releases, clippings, and materials relating to management meetings, and reports on financial, administrative, operational, valuation and real estate matters. Companies represented include JWT subsidiaries such as Hill and Knowlton, Brouillard Communications, Lansdowne, Thompson Recruitment Advertising and JWT Canada, and clients such as Kraft, along with JWT offices in Chicago and Frankfurt. Collection also touches on relations with Gray and Company.
Collection Arrangement
The Herbert Eames Papers are arranged alphabetically by topic, including three main categories: JWT Offices, JWT Subsidiaries, and Meetings. Original folder titles have been retained.
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Advertising Vertical Files
Biographical Information
Corporate Documentation
Frankfurt Office. Hans Ihlefeld Papers
Iconographic Collection
Victor Gutierrez Papers
Writings and Speeches
Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising agencies -- Canada; Advertising -- Canada; Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising -- Germany; Brouillard Communications, Inc.; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; Hill and Knowlton, Inc.; Hindustan Thompson Associates; Gray and Company; J. Walter Thompson Company; Eames, Herbert; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; Kraft Foods Company
- General Files, 1974-1985 and undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes memos, correspondence, contracts, reports, handwritten notes, press releases, clippings and financial documents. Topics covered include relations with Gray and Company and market research opportunities. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Gray and Company, settlement, S.E.C. filing and other files, 1983-1984 and undated (Box 1)
  - JWT Offices, 1978-1984 and undated
    - Asia/Pacific Consolidated 1983-1985 Projections Report, 1983 July 11 (Box 1)
      [Additional Asia/Pacific materials are located with Latin America materials in box 2]
    - Asia/Pacific Regional Offices, Begg Dow Friday, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - Australia, purchase reports for 132 Elizabeth St, Sydney, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Canada, budget information, JWT Company Limited consolidated financial statements, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
      [Additional materials regarding JWT Canada can be found intermixed with files regarding Brouillard Communication and Thompson Recruitment Advertising in Box 2]
    - Chicago
      - General, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
      - Lease expansion, Kraft compensation, 1978-1984 (Box 1)
    - Europe
      - Operational Review, 1984 Oct. 24, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Reports regarding staff development, benefits, finances and new business, 1980-1983 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Frankfurt (Box 2)
      - Financial management review, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Pension plan revision analysis, 1983 (Box 2)
      - Valuation of PR operation, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Hindustan Thompson, annual report for years 1982-1983 and press release, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Hong Kong, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Japan, real estate report, 1983 Nov. 7 (Box 2)
    - Latin America, operational review, Asia/Pacific business review, 1984 (Box 2)
    - London and JWT Group Limited, 1980-1983 (Box 2)
      [Additional materials regarding JWT Group Limited can be found with the JWT subsidiaries folders in Box 3]
    - Malaysia, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Manchester, marketing plan for years 1984-1986, undated, circa 1983 (Box 2)
    - Middle East, office formation and possible merger or takeover of Intermarkets, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
    - Spain, A Plan for a New Structure presentation, 1983 Dec. 1 (Box 2)
    - Turkey and Intermarkets, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
    - USA, operational review including Thompson in Transition speech by Burt Petersen, 1984 (Box 2)
  - JWT Subsidiaries, 1974-1985
    [Includes memos, correspondence, contracts, reports, handwritten notes, press releases, clippings and financial documents.]
    - Brouillard Communications
      - JWT Canada, Thompson Recruitment Advertising, reports, 1984 (Box 2)
        [Additional materials regarding JWT Canada can be found with the JWT offices folders in Box 1]
      - Operational review (1983) and related communications, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
    - Communispond Inc., regarding sale, 1976-1980 (Box 3)
    - European subsidiaries
      - [General files, 1981-1982: Removed to oversize materials box 5] (Box 3)
      - Begg Dow Friday, financial reports, forecasts and assessments, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
      - Euro-Advertising International, 1979-1985 and undated, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Hill & Knowlton and Hill & Knowlton Germany, 1980-1984 (Box 3)
    - JWT Company Limited, consolidated financial statements, 1981 Dec. 31 (Box 3)
      [Additional materials regarding JWT Group Limited can be found with the JWT offices folders in box 2]
    - Lansdowne, contract and correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
    - Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein, Inc., 1974-1983 and undated (Box 3)
    - MRB International, expansion program, undated, circa 1981 (Box 3)
    - Thompson Recruitment Advertising Inc., Begg Dow Friday, Worldwide Agency Inc., 1979-1984 (Box 3)
  - Meetings, 1983-1984
    - Board of Directors Meeting, JWT Canada, 1984 Apr. 13 (Box 3)
    - European Financial Managers Meeting, 1983 Sept. 26-30 (Box 3)
    - European Financial Managers Meeting, 1984 Sept. 24 (Box 4)
    - European Managers Meeting, 1983 May 16-20 (Box 4)
  - Opportunities for JWT in Market Research, report and Simmons Market Research press release and clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 4)